Roman Sypchenko

rs.sypchenko@gmail.com | +1 403-200-8512 | Calgary, AB, Canada www.linkedin.com/in/sypchenko

SUMMARY

Frontend developer with 8+ years of experience leveraging JavaScript to build responsive websites and interactive features that drive business growth and improve UX. I have a strong understanding of modern frontend technologies, including JavaScript, TypeScript and various frameworks such as React (5+ years) and Vue.js (2+ years). Collaborated with both large and small teams.

SKILLS

JavaScript, React.js, Vue.js, Redux, React Hooks, React Router, Styled Components, Next.js, GraphQL, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Figma, Git, Webpack, Gulp, Docker, Jest, Cypress, Node.js, Express, MongoDB.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AUTO1 Group (Europe's leading digital automotive platform), Germany **JavaScript Engineer**, Remote

Dec 2021 - Nov 2022

Build financing tools for large-scale micro-frontend project

- Moved legacy code to new micro-frontend architecture using React.js, TypeScript, GraphQL
- Collaborated with QA team to improve quality of existing components and covered more components by autotests and added more use-cases
- Developed and improved 10+ existing and new reusable components for a custom UI library
- Developed new financing tools and UI features for Backoffice

Tech stack: React.js, React Hooks, React Hooks Form, Next.js, GraphQL, TypeScript, Apollo, Docker, Jest, LESS, HTML, Jenkins, Git, Apollo, GitHub.

Everest Media (Advertising network), Montenegro **Senior Frontend Developer**

Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

Build and contributed high load advertising project

- Led company to use templates and building tools with an internal framework for custom e-commerce shops that reduce page load time by more than 50% and increase the speed of development
- Designed and Implemented an internal framework that increased development speed by 25%
- Mentored a team of 5 front-end developers to improve their technical and soft skills and increased the speed and code quality of project development
- Involved in hiring pipeline: CV screening, interviewing candidates, evaluating tech assessments.

Tech stack: JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, Vue.js, Docker, Webpack, Gulp, Node.js, Git, GitLab, Cypress, Jest, SCSS, HTML, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap.

Finline (Financing company), Ukraine

Oct 2016 – Aug 2020

Senior Frontend Developer

Build and designed financing education platforms (Financing, Crypto)

- Developed UI for a crypto platform that allowed analysis using charts and tools for buying and selling stock and crypto assets
- Designed and developed a visual editor (UML) that allowed auto setup and configure servers and traffic distribution
- Designed and developed an education platform for financing and crypto traders.

Tech stack: JavaScript, React.js, Vue.js, Docker, Jest, Charts.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, Semantic UI

Finline (Financing company), Ukraine

Aug 2014 – Oct 2016

Frontend Developer

- Developed and maintained backoffice and UI tools for our clients that increased the quality of service and product support
- Designed and developed web chat for the support team that allows our client quickly solve issues and get better service

Tech stack: JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, SCSS, SASS, HTML, Chart.js, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, MySQL

EDUCATION

Alfred Nobel University, Dnipro, Ukraine Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Sep 2008 – Jun 2012